They they do it the the right way. They
do it the hard way. And uh they make you
try to earn it at the end of the game.
So, uh we know this will be one of those
physical battles. Um you know, we got to
play smart, take care of the football,
and be very efficient. But, uh he's
always run a good program and we know we
got our hands full. Questions? Have
>> you uh developed any sort of
relationship with him at all just over
your time in the league? I mean, he's
been coaching the Steelers since you've
been playing, but um have you gotten a
chance to know him at all over your
travels?
>> Yeah, but I Yeah, I do uh know him, but
I wouldn't say it's uh something where I
I call him, we talk all the time,
anything like that. Uh I've just got a
ton of respect for him. I know what he's
about and and uh and the way he he goes
about his business. And then, you know,
anybody that I know that's ever come
across, Coach Tomlin speaks so highly of
him. So, um, you know, he's he's, uh,
oneonone.
>> Uh, when you look at them and and and
some of their skill weapons, obviously
DK Metaf, you know, stands out, but
Awell actually leads them in in
receptions. What's the difficulty, Dan,
of of, you know, trying to defend a
running back much like Christian
McCaffrey who who catches so many
footballs and is dangerous like that out
of the back field, much like Gibbs has
become for you guys.
>> Yeah. Well, it it it just gives them
another element, right? the uh gives
them another element and uh that gets
you know if you're able to get the
running back out and he's a good route
runner then you know you get isolated on
a linebacker. Um we're fortunate we got
some pretty good backers here so that
helps but yet uh it's still a matchup
that I would say most offenses are
always looking for in general is can can
you find that? Um and you know I like
Gainwell. He's a good back and he he is
he's versatile. You know he's got
vision. Uh he's pretty sneaky that way.
shifty and and he is a good receiver. Um
and then you know Rogers has done a
great job of finding those throws,
getting the ball out. He's got some big
targets. Metaf is is still he's a load.
He's a weapon. His run after catch is
really showing up this year. I mean,
it's always been there, but a lot more
underneath throws and letting him make
something happen. Um you know, they got
three tight ends over there that that
can block and run and you know um Arthur
Smith's doing a hell of a job. you know,
he's running his system and and it fits
what they're about. It fits what they
do.
>> Unlock the deep ball a little bit there
against the Rams better than he had, you
know, the past several weeks. I'm just
wondering how much of that was schematic
to the opponent or do you think maybe
you've got something sustainable you can
build off of from that performance?
>> A lot of that was opponent, you know, um
it was we just we were going to be able
to get some opportunities with what they
do. Um and we we hit at the right time.
golf saw it, felt that JMO was
outstanding. So was Saint down in the
red zone and it was it just all you know
it was uh it all worked lined up really
well and uh those guys really executed
at a high level you know so it was
everything uh working the way that you
want it to work. Um that was good.
Doesn't mean that those those are not
you know that you don't want them to
show up again but it was kind of the
perfect uh you know
perfect situation. ask about one of your
your running backs, David Montgomery,
and just kind of his you know, how he's
handling his reduced role of sorts, I
guess, uh especially last week and and
maybe the challenges of of getting him
more involved, you know, given how good
Jir is and um you know, only one ball to
go around.
>> Yeah, I mean, David is a pro. David's a
pro. You know, he goes about his
business. He handles it and uh I know
that's not easy. It's not easy. I mean,
you're you're a guy who he's a damn good
back and uh you know, uh you know, every
good player wants their chance to help
the team win and get get some
production. So, I I know that's it can't
be easy. I know it's not easy. Um but
he's a pro. He handles his business and
goes about it and whenever you call his
number, he's ready to go. Um and and
it's something I think about a lot, you
know, is how do we get them all
involved? you know, he's one of those
when when they're all involved, we're
just better. We're a better offense and
uh you know, where where do we get him
touches? Where do we find them? And um
you know, so I do I think about him a
lot.
>> How do you go about getting him more
touches or is it just like you talked
about before, more plays equals more
touches for everyone, you know? Well,
more plays is always going to help, but
you know, I think it's it's some of
those what series, you know, do do it's
one thing to bring him in, but maybe
before that, do we start tagging some
things for him to get him involved early
in and Jaws series, you know, and get
jaw breather and um and then we've used
some of these two back, you know, those
the two back with three receivers. We
we've done some of that. Um, but that's,
you know, that's kind of where we're at
right now.
>> Over the years with with Aaron Rogers at
Ford Field, there are some performances
that would make Lions fans break out in
hives just thinking about him.
>> Mhm.
>> What is he still doing so well that's
made him succeed, made him, you know,
the quarterback of his generation?
>> Well, he plays fast. He plays fast and
he's accurate. I mean, he's always had
the accuracy. He's got such a quick
release. I mean, he can process it like
that and and it's with a flick of the
wrist, the thing is it's into the
receivers's hands uh at a perfect
location to where they can do damage
with uh once they get it into their
hands. So, um that that that has gone
nowhere. You know, his ability to to get
it out and and play fast is still there.
Very much there.
>> Yeah, Tomlin mentioned that they've done
a lot of research on Jack Campbell
specifically this week. What do you
think of just the attention he's really
starting to attract externally and how
flexible he's been in the situations you
put him in?
>> Well, he's uh we've known it. I mean, we
have. I mean, he's uh you know, that's
um we we we know how valuable he is for
us and what he does. Um you know, I
mean, he's he's a rugged player for us,
man. He's a durable, rugged, productive
player. Um you know, and I mentioned
this, I think last week, and it's still
the same thing. He's taken more reps
than anybody on our team to this point,
which is uh and those are not u easy
reps, you know, but fortunately he is
he's built well, you know, he's built to
handle it and uh
and and so that's, you know, I'm happy
for for him in that regard because he is
getting noticed and he is uh he he
deserves credit for the way he's
playing, but uh but we've known it, you
know, here in this building what he's
about. You guys have given up 30 points
each of the last four games and over
that span you've given up the most
passing yards in the league. Um how much
has that reduced the margin of error for
the offense?
>> Yeah, a ton. You know, a ton. And I I
think you know this goes back to last
week was um yeah it it is minimal. And
when you struggle to run the ball then
to keep up or to stay ahead of them, you
have to be perfect in the pass game. you
know, we have no margin for error to not
have a completion or miss on a shot play
or give up a sack. Like we we don't have
that, you know. Um and that's very
difficult if if you're asking that of
your pass game and today's game and the
league the way it's set up. So, um it
does it puts a lot of strain on you, but
at the same time, you find the run game
like I talked about in the third
quarter. you reduce the stress off the
defense and now you make their offense
onedimensional because you're up two
scores late in the third. So that's why
it all goes hand in hand and where
offensively we can help the defense and
in turn the defense helps the offense
and then you you gain a little
confidence. You find your way and
so
>> it's just a walk through today but uh
mahogany was listed as as full go um
chances
>> full go walk through today. [laughter]
what do you the chances he can be back
this week and what what sort of lift can
he give you when he
>> Yeah, I mean we're hopeful. We'll we'll
know a lot more tomorrow. You know, I
know by last week uh certainly, you
know, was okay. That looked pretty good,
but also knew he he wasn't ready. Um
so, I mean, we're hopeful. I I don't
It's a good question. I mean, I'm I'm
kind of I'm hoping it looks pretty good.
I hope he feels good, but we'll we'll
know more really by Friday. So full
speed tomorrow and Friday, he'll he'll
go through and then we'll see see if he
can go.
>> I knew the 13 personnel going into last
week was was going to be the thing. Um
some of your guys in the locker room
just said that the stress that it put on
them was was a little bit too much to
overcome. What Pittsburgh runs at second
most in the league. You know, what can
you take away from last week and the
corrections coming out of that game that
can be applied here? Well, there there's
some certainly there's there's a some
schematic things we will do a little
different and that we know we we can do
a little different that we think can
help. All right? And I'm not going to
dive into all that. Um but then just
there again some of the uh some of our
fits, some of the keys, some of those
little things um just got a little dirty
on some of our guys. gave our guys, you
know, there's it's a little muddy and
and man, stay focused on what your keys
are and what you're supposed to be
looking at. And it doesn't mean it's
easy, but it's going to help
significantly. A lot of that goes a long
way. And if you don't see a ton of it,
it can get on you, you know, and uh so I
I think seeing it actually was probably
one of the best thing getting ready for
this game as we just came out of a full
game with it, you know. Um, and and so I
think I think everything I think we can
help them a little bit here. I think
seeing it last week is big and I think
we re we we focus on those guys in their
keys, man. Your eyes where your eyes
belong. Where's your fit? Um, that
that'll all help.
>> You've had some stuff at left guard
maybe disrupting continuity in the back
half of the year, but how do you feel
like that's been progressing over the
last six, seven weeks or so?
>> Uh, just at the left guard. Well, I
>> protection in general despite maybe some
of the health disrupting.
>> Yeah. I mean, it it's look, I'm always
going to want more. That's me. And cuz I
don't ever want golf getting hit. So,
I'm always going to, you know, you'd
love to come out of the season and say
there's no quarterback hits. Well,
that's not a reality. But, you're always
going to want more. Um, and look, it's
not the easiest thing to roll guards in
there. Um, and you know, you get an
injury, now it's a new guard, and now
it's, you know, this this one Cologne's
in, now Frasier's in. And so that's not
easy, but I think we're doing the right
thing and doing what we feel like is is
giving us the best chance at this point.
It's not perfect, but I I think it's
where we're at and what we need to do.
>> Looks like you started Gio's clock uh
this week. Just kind of curious, you
know, what what are you looking for him
in these final three weeks of the
regular season? I think for Gio, it's he
needs he needs reps. Practice reps. Get
out there against our defense against
Davenport and Hutch and real time
practice. There's not a ton of them. And
um it's not like training camp, but God,
he just needs reps, man. He cannot get
enough reps. And if if we're able to use
him or there's something there uh this
year, that's a bonus. It's really about
getting him, man. it will this set him
up better for next year, you know, for
training camp going into that next year.
Um, that's that's really it.
>> Yeah, Dan, we've talked a lot about the
team not losing back to back games, but
the last two months uh
talking about it.
[laughter]
>> I am wondering about uh growing this
team and your experience, what goes into
the recipe of uh stacking wins.
>> Well, you got to win the first one. you
know, like I mentioned the other day, we
got to win this one to have a chance to
win the next one. Um, so that that's
that's really where it all starts, man.
It's uh, you know, like I I told the
team, it's um, you know, it it's it's
really it's one week, it's one game, and
it's one win. That's all we can focus
on. We got, you know, let's go back to
the drawing board, go back to the
fundamentals, the things we talked
about, man, urgency out here. Um, and
and let's go, man. We got to get ready.
just a rugged team that's coming in
here, a physical team, and they've
always been that way. They played bully
ball. We just came out of a game where
they played physical and uh and we lost
that game. And so I know what that tape
says, you know, I know what Pittsburgh's
looking at. So that that's what we got
to be preparing for and understand the
attitude you're going to have to have.
[music]
>> [music]